this is software engineering radio the
podcast for professional developers on
the web at sc-radio.net
c-radio is brought to you by the IEEE
computer Society by IEEE software
Magazine online at computer.org software
welcome to software engineering radio my
guest today is William falcon William is
the CEO of lightning AI whose platform
we will discuss today William is on
leave from earning his PhD at NYU New
York University
his research there was at the
intersection of AI and Neuroscience
previously William co-founded and was
the CTO of an AI startup called next-gen
vest and before that he was a software
engineer at Goldman sex let's start with
an introduction
what is pi torch and then what is
lightning so if you're building neural
networks you need a framework to
basically help you do automatic
differentiation so pytorch is I guess
it's a lot of things but for people
working in deep learning it's really a
way to build neural networks in a way
that you can automatically differentiate
and compute gradients so it's a
computational library I guess and
lightning is a way to organize pytorch
code so that you have flexibility
modularity and the structure of the code
allows teams to work together and scale
their workloads so what we've discovered
is that training things like Foundation
models llms diffusion and so on can't
really be done through scripts easily
and this is how people normally code you
actually need to structure like
lightning itself to do it this is why
even companies like Facebook use
lighting internally even though they
create a pytorch right great and just
kind of frame what we're talking about
here can you think of some specific
projects or products that are made with
lightning and pytorch that just kind of
give us a frame of reference throughout
the conversation yeah so we have around
10 000 companies using lightning today
to train models so one big example is
obviously Facebook itself So Meta a lot
of the stuff that you touch a meta today
uses lightning to train under the hood
now they use a combination of other
things of course but it's a big part of
their stack their self-driving car
companies there's major Banks there's
retailers guess who can I talk about
publicly so these are all public repos
that I'm talking about right now so you
can go to Nvidia there's a bunch of
repos that use lightning so Nemo is a
library by Nvidia that is actually built
on top of lightning which is cool
you can actually browse through our
GitHub repo I don't know how much I can
say about clients without their
permission on this but one major public
example that came out recently is so if
you guys know uh stable diffusion right
a really cool company called stability I
built that and all that code is pi torch
lighting right so those models for
training you see lightning as well great
so that's a pretty broad adoption right
there before we talk about lighting in
detail let's discuss deep learning in
general and the challenges of developing
and productionizing deep learning
applications today focusing maybe some
more on the operational challenges for
an in-depth introduction to deep
learning let me refer you to episode 391
Jeremy Howard on deep learning and fast
Ai and here are three other past
episodes related to machine learning
episode 534 Andy dang on AI and ml
observability episode 522 know a gift on
ML apps and episode 473 Mike delbasso on
feed stores
so firstly today in 2022 how much of the
machine learning industry and focus is
on deep learning as opposed to other
types of machine learning well I'll
start with the easy answer if you have
data already and if you've already been
doing basic machine learning then people
are starting to look into deep learning
right now what I'm seeing across
industry is that companies in finance
Healthcare self-driving car they're
pretty deep learning already they've
already adopted a lot of this even
retailers there are some industries that
are lagging but it's mostly because I
don't have the data collection efforts
in place so I think before you can do
deep learning you basically need the
data now that may not be true now with
Foundation models where you can actually
fine-tune but you know that stuff
changes every week so things are
changing rapidly there now if you apply
the Deep learning definition more
broadly which is differentiable programs
well logistic regression right you have
linear regression those can all be
written in by torch so you can actually
distribute the code across gpus and
everything else so if you put those
rhythms into that category then it's a
pretty broad use case already okay and
to flip it around are there application
domains where you think deep learning
should not be used just to kind of frame
the scope a few years ago I would have
said an LP because before Transformers
2018 before that paper came out I would
have said NLP probably mostly because
there was not a lot ability to transfer
learn so you had to like have a lot of
data to train stuff and I had a next gen
vest we used a lot of feedback then
right so we were deploying NLP models
and you needed a ton of conversations to
do stuff today that's not necessarily
true anymore so where do you not need
deep learning it's maybe less I think
you can apply deep learning now to
everything but it's more about like are
you going to get a massive boost it's in
certain areas so like random forests are
still great I think XG boost is also
still great right so sometimes deep
learning algorithm will be a little bit
Overkill when you have those so no
matter what we do I'm an AI researcher
even and I do deep learning I always
start with the Baseline that's always
like linear regression to random force
or something like that just to see what
we can do beyond that okay you mentioned
next-gen vest I think that was a company
you founded previously can you just
mention what they did so we were a
service for helping high school students
figure out how to pay for college
low-income students so we would go into
low-income high schools throughout the
us and we would basically give seminars
and onboard the students there into our
platform which is All Tech space so you
use you know these are welcome students
where a lot of them don't have
smartphones or laptops so it'll be like
regular Nokia phones that kind of thing
they would text with us and we pair them
with a money Mentor so we called it like
a financial advisor so you know people
that we trained and they would help you
figure out how to apply for scholarships
how to get money like we help people who
are like so good that they didn't even
know they could apply to like Harvard or
like ivy league universities and so
we're really trying to democratize
education and the way that we scaled
that we had at the time about 65 000
users and we only had about 60 money
mentors right we're having a ton of
conversations daily so we use a lot of
NLP to basically do that we didn't do
like automated chats we did a lot of
like human in the loop to help them like
get more context about what they had to
answer and like things to say to them
right today I still wouldn't do it fully
automated because even this like GPT
models and llms they hallucinate a lot
right so you don't just want to drop
these things without any human
supervision yeah that's my impression
that sort of human assisted AI is going
to be super common going forward for
quite a while yeah absolutely and it's
interesting because like you know the
way I think about these Foundation
models so you might have heard of the
fusion and llms like they have a bug and
a really nasty bug right now which is
they don't know they're just going to
make something up right so we call that
a hallucination it's not great in text
because it'll be like yeah I don't know
someone did X and that actually didn't
happen and they say with so much
confidence that it can trick you but for
the fusion where it's generative art it
actually becomes a feature because like
hallucinating actually makes the image
look more interesting right so it's kind
of fascinating in my view how those
things are evolving yeah I can see the
difference there where Precision is is
required and maybe where it isn't as
essential so talking about optimization
what does it mean to optimize a deep
learning model we know from regular code
we're generally talking about the speed
that it takes the memory that it uses is
that the same with deep learning or are
there other you know specific types of
optimization we're talking about yes so
it really depends how deep you want to
go I guess I think today you don't have
to worry about a lot of this because of
libraries like pytorch and lightning
right where we handle a lot of this
under the hood but if you really want to
optimize steep learning and depends on
the scale I'm talking scale of like
hundreds of gpus or thousands right if
you're talking about single GPU or a few
I think that's very straightforward or
optimize but to optimize something like
multi-node training where you have
thousands of gpus and this is the stuff
that lightning was built on in 2019
right so today's a big deal but like
back then we were really pushing the
edge you have to optimize the way that
the data gets loaded makes sure that it
doesn't bottleneck the training
especially in the cloud right so a lot
of like our Cloud offering is actually
that's what it solves it makes sure that
like we do all that stuff under the hood
for you and then once you have the data
on the machines then you have to
optimize literally like what actually
the models are doing and that's going to
be through the algorithm itself like how
are you Computing the gradients like
what type of operations are there are
you broadcasting or not so it gets
really really performance heavy there
you can even optimize Cuda kernels if
you want to fuse operations or something
like that and then the networking itself
is a big bottleneck as well so it kind
of goes all in so like if you need like
millisecond training or millisecond
latency for inference or something deep
learning it's actually a lot of work it
takes it has a lot of moving Parts like
I think regular software engineering
generally doesn't right and then not to
mention the math that we're taking for
granted because the model already gave
you the math right so you're just kind
of like black boxing that thing
yeah so how about training versus
inferencing is optimization strictly in
inferencing sort of production issue or
maybe iterating during this training
phase is optimization also a factor
there it really depends on your use case
so let's say you're like CNN or
something like that right or BuzzFeed or
something you process news immediately
right Wall Street Journal and you get
the news immediately and now you need to
train a model and then recommend things
for that so you now have literally a few
minutes to train that model and then
deploy it because like by the time that
you're done that maybe still other
people may have picked it up right so
you want to drive traffic to your site
so it just really depends on the use
case like for those guys real-time
training like as quickly as possible is
super super important whereas for
someone like maybe yeah even fraud
detection I would say like unless you're
a bank and you're doing fraud detection
you may only need to train that model
once a day and it's fine right so you
don't actually need it to be super fast
in France also it kind of matters
depends on the use case right like if
you're in a self-driving car well you
really need to do like kind of real-time
inference like sub millisecond inference
right if you're a website powering
something like stable diffusion where
you put a prompt and you generate an
image like users can wait a few seconds
for that it's not really a problem right
so it just kind of comes down to the
specific use case yeah so I wasn't
thinking of real-time training at all my
recent exposure to AI are models the AI
art and chat GTP and in those cases I
think they do a huge expensive training
run and then the model can be used for
months or longer maybe years but I see
what you're saying about needing to
train almost all the time that's a
different use case even with those use
cases like you still want to fine tune
the model so if you can right like if
you have no data no money then take the
pre-trained model if you have some data
on some money you still want to fine
tune it to make it more appropriate for
what you're doing
fine tuning is literally training it's
just not training for months it's
training for a few hours but even
trading on llm fine-tuning it where that
model you know the way I explain it is
like training like an svm or like a
regular kind of convolutional network
it's kind of like cooking a steak right
it's like it fits on a pen like you can
do that and if you want to train many of
those you can just get many pens right
and then kind of have separate Stakes
for that training on the LM is kind of
like you have the whole cow there it
just doesn't fit on the thing like you
just can't do it right you need like a
grill or something bigger so that model
is so big that I just kind of fit in one
machine so you actually have to
distribute it across machines even if
you're only going to train for like five
minutes right it's just the size of the
models now you have techniques like deep
speed or fstp where it will actually
offload GPU memory into CPU for example
to actually try to fit these models into
it this is like a very active area of
research but yeah I mean I would even
fine-tune if I could right if I had the
money and the data I would still
recommend people fine-tune yeah so I
definitely see optimization being
important to training and inferencing
but how about just sort of deep into
early development you're still
experimenting and then you get something
you like and you're going to make this
transition to production what sort of
concerns come to mind or do you have to
kind of keep it in good shape sort of no
matter what phase of development you're
in yeah I mean I think my main concern
is how you actually go through that
process because if you use notebooks
like yeah maybe it's nice because it's
cool to like scratch paper to try some
things out
but actually putting that into
production or even training it at scale
is impossible right so I recommend
people just always use scripts directly
right like write your own Python scripts
do it that way and and we encourage
everyone to do that it just I think
that's the biggest bottleneck I would
say it's like okay even though you went
and POC and you did scratch paper for a
while you should still take the time to
then write something clean that code up
and make it scalable so you can actually
go do stuff with it so probably the main
concern is people leaving the code in
notebooks are not doing anything after
that
because the other stuff I think is a lot
easier to handle yeah I can see that and
you talked about distributed training
with you know hundreds or more gpus is
that a big transition point where maybe
you can train on one GPU for a while and
you're sort of happy with that and then
you scale it up and you have to to make
that jump or is it more of a smooth use
as many gpus as needed in terms of
what's been done historically exactly so
normally the number of gpus are a
function of how big the model is and how
much data you have and to some extent
your willingness to pay right if the
model fits on one GPU so fine you can
use one GPU now the problem is how much
data do you have if you have like a few
thousand examples then that one GPU
model will train in a few hours maybe
and you'll be done but if you have
billions of examples now suddenly that
becomes six months of training so if you
go to two gpus that becomes three months
so you go to four gpus that becomes
month and a half right so it just
depends do you want your results in a
month and a half an hour if you go to an
hour you're going to need like 2 000
gpus right so it just depends on your
particular use case I think this is
where lightning shines because to you it
doesn't actually matter it's a number
that you change in lightning you say one
or a thousand and we take care of the
rest so it just comes down to like your
appetite for time and money I guess yeah
I've definitely seen that in non-machine
learning cases where you have a batch
process and there's certain bright lines
like can you do two iterations a day you
know or do you have to do one per day or
so it really can you do four per day you
know it really does matter sometimes how
many hours yeah and I think even in the
research phase like there is a POC face
where you're just trying to see if this
thing is going to work I think deep
learning is a little bit different than
I don't know traditional machine
learning I guess where the hyper
parameters matter a lot like if you mess
up the I don't know in an svm the
setting for you know the Gap like how
big that is or the decision boundary
like that's not really going to change
things stat drastically for you whereas
in deep learning the wrong learning rate
it'll just give you guard garbage the
whole time right so you have to do more
hyper parameter sweeps usually when you
get these pre-built models they already
have the settings in there but they may
not work for your data set so some
people get like 70 and they're like okay
fine but you know you could have tuned
the hyper parameters tuning the hyper
parameters means you actually have to
run parallel versions of that model so
I'll take that same model on one GPU and
then change the hyper parameters and run
it on a separate GPU so that's going to
limit your iteration speed so if you
need to try 100 hyper parameters then do
you have 100 GPU so you can do it all at
once or you're gonna have to sequence
them right so that's where I would start
thinking about distributed as well okay
I mentioned before we had an episode on
ML apps but for the purposes of the rest
of this conversation what are these
operational tasks whether during
training or production can you give
examples of some ml Ops tasks that can
soak up a lot of time or take a lot of
effort yes so again really depends on
your workflow I'm going to pick a pretty
complicated one you have to move data
around you have to process it you have
to extract features maybe you store
those features maybe you store the
output of that into like an S3 bucket
and then from there you train a model
the model training part itself how do
you get the gpus how do you get the
hardware how do you link up the data
what permissions do you have like should
you have access to that data or not is
that model even allowed if you're in
finance are you track hacking everything
that happened to that model so when
auditing happens like you can actually
explain what's going on to it so it's
not as simple as just train a model and
I think this is where a lot of people
get cut up because they'll be like oh I
can train this model and they like go do
this somewhere and then suddenly they're
like stitching together a billion tools
to get all of these things done and it's
just impossible to maintain right and so
there's I think the complexity is going
to add up depending on the field that
you're in even if you're in healthcare
you may not even have access to the
machines because the data cannot leave
the machines right so there are a lot of
nuances that go into this a lot of what
we do on the platform is basically
abstract that stuff away so that you
know we work with tons of customers to
make sure that this is already embedded
into the tools and like true to the
lighting way all you have to think about
is hey solving cancer whatever you're
doing with that all these other elements
that go along with it right and I
actually think ml apps will get more
complicated because you know we're
starting to apply regulation to these
things right we're starting to learn
what should not be done remember this is
like a brand new field it's like the
wild west no one knows what's going to
change right so if you're not future
proof maybe a year from now whatever you
built no longer can pass whatever test
some agency puts together for models now
right yeah and I can imagine that part
of the issue is segmenting from a hiring
point of view what are the skill sets
you need to hire for and maybe back in
the day having the PHD researcher be the
same person as doing operations was
possible but I imagine in any company of
a significant size today you have
different roles for these different
things yeah and you know the thing is so
complicated with the learning that like
if you look at the company structure
that we have we have people across the
full stack we have experts in
infrastructure we have experts at the pi
torch level like we literally just
started a pytharch theme with the old
chord lead at pytorch and that means
that things can be optimized for
end-to-end most companies don't have
that right so you're not going to have
people who are like expert Cuda kernel
people or compiler people or distributed
training people or any of that so you're
basically going to be offloading a lot
of that to the tools like the open
source thing so we take care of that for
you and I actually think it's great
because it lowers the barrier to entry
like in my world you have an undergrad
in CS who can go build the most
complicated diffusion model in the world
without really having to deal with all
the things happen under the hood it's
kind of like today when you you go drive
to the store you're not like learning
fluid mechanics unlike physics to do
that right yeah and something that's
maturity and some of it's maybe the
demand for these skills is increasing so
let's get into lightning in particular
let's talk about where did this idea for
pytorch lightning come from when it was
called pytorch lightning and just kind
of the story about how it evolved into
lightening the platform yeah for sure so
I was an undergrad at Columbia
University and working on computational
Neuroscience this was around 2015 I want
to say 2014 2015. and you know I I was
working on neural decoding so we were
measuring activity in the brain in our
case the retina and we were trying to
figure out what produced those neural
activity they're like spikes right so
it's called the reverse process of going
from spikes to the input is called a
neural decoding well the process of
decoding we were experimenting with
neural networks right specifically vaes
and Gans at the time we ended up
publishing a paper in Europe's about
this that was like one of the first
papers to do this with deep learning
models and you know back then I started
writing code so that I wouldn't have to
refactor anything when I moved to a new
project right and this became I called
it like research lab back then and this
was like my internal project it actually
was written first in Tiano so it was not
a pie torch right because that didn't
exist back then so stiano and then
eventually we wrote it in tensorflow
because the models were too slow in
piano so we wanted to move super super
fast and that was really good I mean it
did speed things up but it was really
hard to work with especially on the
debugging side so then when pytorch came
out or we wrote it in pytorch and kind
of kept that Library around for a while
it was always my personal library and
then in 2018 when I started my PhD you
know I was working with kyung hinsho and
Jan Lacuna at NYU and and Cho was like
hey why don't we maybe open sources and
like let other people in the lab use it
right and so we started working on that
and then basically you know kind of made
it Open Source Early 2019 I want to say
for the lab for silver NYU silver people
that started using it and then a few
months later I joined Facebook AI
research and then kind of brought it
there and continue using it then a few
teams at fair starting adopting it and
at the time what I was trying to do was
Train on YouTube like literally all of
YouTube the biggest model I could find
you know there was a lot of
complications for getting the data so we
ended up doing something different but
back then the models that we were
training were one model and about a
thousand gpus 10 24 gpus and I was doing
sweeps of like five or six of those
models right so it was like a few
thousand gpus being used at any one time
and that was like a research intern and
I was like this one person blowing up
the cluster the other three teams were
like full-blown like five six person
teams that were like just starting to
reach that scale as well and I worked
closely with a lot of teams like
fairseek you know pytorch team itself I
was sitting next to them and most of the
time there so a lot of the knowledge
gets embedded into lighting during that
time for distributed training and then
it kind of takes off across other
companies Finance everything else
Facebook itself starts using it more and
then you know later that year late 2019
basically there was a lot of demand from
companies to say Hey how do we do this
on the cloud how do we scale like cool
like yes I can set this number to a
thousand but like how do I actually get
the machines and there's so much going
into that right so I decided to start
the company and back then we started
basically helping people train models in
the cloud right so this is called grid
and that went well and then basically my
vision for what we wanted to do was not
necessarily just train models right it
was really how do you work with every
tool out there every single open source
tool every single private tool that you
have to get it to work together how to
build like an operating system basically
right and we kind of introduced that
idea like I think it's common today and
people take this for granted but
remember before lightning you didn't
just get tensorboard out of the box with
things like we introduced that idea we
introduced the trainer as well right so
we started embedding all of these other
secondary tools together to work into a
cohesive experience and so people
started getting this notion of a
platform at that point right but through
the framework level which is really
interesting so then we generalized that
idea and we said well you know it turns
out that this Paradigm that we
implemented is not just good for
training it's actually good for the
whole whole thing and so we launched
lightning AI basically as a platform
where you can train models and then
build full-blown apps AI apps right and
so what people know spites are citing
today has been renamed to lightning and
in there you now have three classes that
you didn't have before before you have
lightning module and then the trainer
right to train models now you also have
a lightning work and a lightning flow
those two things introduce something
called like a reactive Paradigm so if
you're worked on like react.js it's
basically like react for cloud where you
can actually build full-blown apps and
apps is a weird word but what we mean is
workflows right so even if you're doing
research it means I can train models
fine-tune them I can train all alarms
monitor if they fail or not so it's kind
of the subtraction layer that actually
allows you to automate a lot of the
operational aspects of those all through
playing python so all of this kind of
grew out of that and I think
holistically the goal for me is that if
you're a scientist you only have to be a
scientist and the thing that you need to
know like biology or chemistry and you
don't have to learn anything else and be
an expert at that and then then let the
tools do the rest for you right that's
on the science side yeah yeah going sort
of way back you mentioned you're talking
about the number of gpus you were using
and you mentioned something like six
sweeps or what what does the sweeps mean
in this case yeah so I took a model that
model was trending on a thousand gpus
maybe using a learning rate of like 0.02
and then I want to try learning rate
0.01 and 0.04 and something else so I at
the same time run that model with
different learning rates I'm parallel so
now I have four models each model and a
thousand gpus but each one has a
different learning rate at once so it's
an experiment it's for experiments right
what I'm trying to see is how does the
learning rate affect convergence is it
going to slow it down sometimes it'll
say they even converge sometimes it
blows up so it's very r d process and am
I right that the learning rate is a
hyper parameter where a hyper parameter
means something that you are explicitly
setting outside of the learning process
is that the correct terminology exactly
yeah so you give give the learning
process some parameters like the number
of layers the size of the image right
and then the model kind of gets created
to fit those requirements okay and you
mentioned lightning module which I was
going to ask about in a little bit but
to stick to an introductory level here
what are the steps to create a new
lightning project or sort of what are
the prerequisites before you can set up
a lightning project yeah so first thing
to keep in mind is lightning module is
an organization layer in pytorch it's
not an abstraction right so it's only
organized in The Code by doing that
you're getting rid of a lot of
boilerplates so if you already have a
pytorch project you're basically going
to go into the inner loop so the part of
the house like right where you get the
batch of data from there until you do
backward dot backward that part goes
into the training step of the lighting
module it's a method on this class and
you just put all that information in
there and then you get rid of everything
that has to do with accelerators like
that Cuda dot CPU all of that because
lightning will automatically handle that
4 for you which makes it Hardware
agnostic then if you have a validation
Loop so if you're doing something like
validation or even cross-validation you
can basically take that code and put it
into a validation step and this is kind
of what most people do and then if
you're in research you usually have a
test set because you're publishing a
paper or something you also have a test
Loop there so that's called a test step
so those are the ingredients that you
need to create a lighting module so it's
like a recipe for a model that means
that everything else does not the
computational graph because that's
literally what you put in there it's
abstracted away in the trainer the
trainer will execute the training Loop
to do that right and so it automatically
will handle that now here's something
that's a little bit different from what
we've done in the past so from basically
like 2012 to 2019 all we did in research
and deep learning was try to figure out
better computational graphs meaning like
does this network have one layer or two
or three does it have skip connections
whatever so all of that you could spend
all your time on the lightning module
messing with right and so if most people
you're doing deep learning that's kind
of what they're doing in 2021 I think or
2020 we introduced GPT GPT is Bert with
a ton of data right now that's not
discrediting anything because that
problem was scaling that model to that
much data actually requires a lot of
engineering that engineering is usually
handed by the trainer and lightning so
what happened at that time is if people
started working on that kind of research
where you're trying to figure out how do
I do gradient distribution how do I
offload gradients or activations right
kind of lightning gets in the way
because it wasn't designed for that
right the trainer was meant to abstract
that away from you but sometimes people
are like a little bit annoyed at that
you've run into this if you started
playing with Gans as well or reinforcer
learning or something like that it's
kind of like the trainer gets in their
way a bit so what we've introduced is
something called fabric which is
basically a way for you to build your
own trainer so lightning fabric is kind
of like that gradient step between plain
pytorch and then lightning module so you
can basically start with plain pie torch
and add fabric to basically get your
lightning modules callbacks and all the
accelerator stuff handled for you but
now you have full control over the
python Loop so now you can actually do
the research for distributed training
and all of that so you can basically end
up writing your own trainer and if you
don't care about that kind of work then
you just use our trainer and then you're
good to go okay thinking about best
practices or a new user possibly making
a mistake is there any thing that you
hear people doing and you're thinking oh
boy don't do it that way I'm in terms of
lightning it's like pitfalls like I
think the main Pitfall is when people
start learning about deep learning they
kind of go through this process of
learning the raw pie torch first which I
think is fine but then they you know you
should do that to understand what you're
doing because you're gonna write like a
training Loop and it's going to be very
basic now the problem is you're going to
think that that's enough to actually do
what you want to do and it feels simple
but the second you try to actually do
something meaningful like for a company
that's not going to work right and so
the problem that people end up doing is
that they think that that simple example
will generalize to something meaningful
that it can actually train at scale
unless you're like literally a PhD in
this or you've been doing deep learning
for a long time it's going to be
extremely difficult to get everything
right like when do you checkpoint how do
you do backwards what happens in
distributed training how do you
aggregate gradients how do you do early
stopping in distributed training there's
a lot of nuances that go into this right
so this is where we would basically
recommend people once you have the
working knowledge just switch to the
lightning module because now the area
for error for you is like dramatically
decreased all you're going to mess up on
is literally the model definition and
the training process but you're not
going to mess up in any of the other
hard things that just take a long time
to learn like in what order do you call
things and it's really easy to mess
things up and it's just super subtle you
just won't see that it's absolutely
wrong yeah that actually leads to a
question I think I had elsewhere which
is like what is the nature of bugs with
deep learning like how does it differ
from a regular software application
which you might think of crashing or not
returning any output or things like that
what do you actually see in deep
learning that you consider a bug that
you have to track down and fix sure so
software engineering you basically have
two bugs you have logic which a compiler
can't catch for you like if you added
wrong or you did a for Loop wrong or
recursions wrong and then like syntax
errors which a compiler will catch for
you right even with python you can do
these kind of things now okay so that's
kind of it now the other errors on deep
learning are okay even though let's say
you wrote your code and the logic is
good and the compiler says everything
checks out your math could be wrong so
like you're not gonna know like did you
multiply or add who knows right did you
do a matrix multiply instead and you
should have done an inverse or something
so that's the first bug that's going to
come out if you're writing your models
you're going to run into this if you're
not you're not going to because we've
already done that for you right the
models are going to be written by people
who know exactly what they're doing
there so hopefully that part of it is
gone now the loss function and
everything else that you're attaching to
it you can still mess up so that's the
first element of it the second element
is the data right so you might be
pushing data through the model but like
if you didn't transform it then it's not
going to work right so if you didn't
normalize the data if you didn't put
into the right structure even like
sometimes it'll crash because the
dimensions are wrong that's not what I'm
talking about I'm talking like if it's
an image for example did you remove the
colors did you Jitter things those kind
of transforms if you do those wrong
that's also not going to work so it's
super super subtle and then after that
you have the kind of like unteen bugs
when you go to the cloud right so let's
say you're training on multi-node and
you're like cool this is nothing's
breaking everything's working exactly
except that it's taking four hours but
then what you don't know is that your
networking is wrong and it's actually
you have a bug in there and now your
training could actually be taken one
hour but you just didn't set up the
networking correctly right so there's
just so many nuances here that just
depends kind of what you're going
through it's a lot more complicated to
get these things running okay and let's
dive into the lighting module in a
second but I want to ask first what
other Frameworks or libraries does
lightning integrate with or more to the
point you know what would you expect to
see people using in concert with
lightning yeah so the traditional
pytorch lightning lightning module
trainer integrates with any experiment
manager that's out there so all of them
are supported tensorboard and so on any
model so you can find two models from
any Library you want open Ai and so on
you can bring them in it's like three
lines of code to fine tune or train
these things torch Vision Etc what else
should we integrate with all the
accelerators so gpus hpus tpus we have
really tight Partnerships with all the
people who build the accelerators so
that they're actually pretty much sorted
out before they launch so that by the
time they launch you already have access
to them in lightning which is really
cool and then NASA mentioned now we've
evolved the project that it's called
lightning now so on that side of it with
the lightning work and the lightning
flow you can actually integrate any
framework even like tensorflow you can
actually train tensorflow models with
lightning now right you can train
tensorflow on the cloud you can do Jacks
you can do anything really as long as
it's machine learning you can do numpy
sklearn all of it right so that was the
original vision is we wanted lighting to
be able to leave this kind of like
central nervous system that everything
can work through I mean that's kind of
what it's become today so no matter what
tool you're using it's definitely going
to be able to work together you'll get
the modularity you get the abstraction
you get the fun of having the lightning
handle all the hard things for you
you mentioned tensorboard can you
explain what that is just for sure so
tensorboard is a way you know to plot
like your experiment outputs I guess so
like a way that you know that deep
learning models have finished training I
guess is to monitor convergence so you
usually have a metric you're optimizing
towards which I guess it's another way
of optimizing what you asked earlier
there's like literally the math way of
optimizing so if you're training a model
it means you're reducing the error
between an expected output and the
actual output of the model when that
error goes to zero you've converts right
now that's like a very crude high level
version of this you can monitor other
metrics but like whatever metric you're
monitoring here you can actually plot
that and see it going to zero and see
the slope of it and you need libraries
to do that right so tensorboard is one
such Library
So when you say see it going to zero
this is presumably as you get deeper
deeper into the training process the
model is getting more refined or better
and then you're maybe testing it or
evaluating it exactly and like I said
you may not be monitoring something that
goes to zero you may be saying hey my
accuracy needs to go up so maybe it goes
up to 100 right so it just depends on
what's important to you but yes it's
about a Min or a Max of some
quantitifiable Metric that you care
about and you watch that change over
time okay let's talk about some details
feel free to steer me to what you think
is is more relevant but can you explain
what the torch and then module is I
guess this is what lightning extends or
improves on but just from the pie torch
point of view like what is that class or
module yeah so it allows you to Define
arbitrary operations on a computational
graph and it lets you chain them
together right so if you think about
what's happening under the hood is back
propagation right so you compute some
activations on the forward pass and then
you figure out how to do assignments of
those errors on the backward pass so you
figure out what knobs do I have to tweak
to minimize the error so the net module
basically gives you like notes on that
graph that like interconnect and allows
the automatic differentiation to go
between those notes so it's I don't know
I guess the highway for the math under
the hood okay and then lightning module
extends that or wraps it what's the
right terminology yeah so it extends it
so that you get all this added benefits
to it right so you get the abstractions
it allows the training process to know
what to call when that structure of the
program allows us to optimize it for you
there's something important here which
is I think it's not obvious to people
but
flexibility and performance are always
at odds if you want ultimate flexibility
you're very very likely to not have the
highest performance unless you really
really know what you're doing right like
really like like if you like literally
work at Nvidia and like write Cuda
Cardinals all day right
so flexibility is something that we want
as researchers I mean I want that as an
AI research I want the most flexibility
that I can get
but not at expensive performance
performance is something that you
usually get through structure in your
code that's how you're going to get that
so lightning is the lighting modules
that's what it's doing it's trying to
give you that hybrid between all the
flexibility that you need but the
structure enough so that we can actually
optimize the code for you
okay looking at the lightning module
sections I guess like the central for
our train validate test and predict can
you kind of just talk about are those
temporal steps that a researcher would
do one after another or is that the
training does those four steps or how
does that work so the trainer is kind of
running this workflow for you it's a
training workflow where it takes a batch
of training data and it feeds it to the
model and then it takes the outputs out
of that computes some loss for it and
then it like back props that loss
through the model
so that will happen for every batch of
data so trains updates trains updates
and so on every one of those we're
calling a step so in the training
process we call that a training step so
lightning is going to give you the data
and then you just figure out what you
need to do with that data how you're
going to process it and then you send it
back to the training process which is a
trainer and the trainer will like do the
back propagation for you and automate
update all the other things with fabric
you have control over that you don't
need to use a trainer you kind of need
to know what you're doing but you can
call that stuff yourself now
now the same thing applies to validation
and testing
it really depends on the workflow that
you're doing for example when I my
research is mostly in self-supervised
learning and in that workflow I tend to
train an epoc over like imagenet for
example or like a big data set and at
the end of the epoch I validate
sometimes if the apoc is long enough so
just to clarify any Puck is when you go
through all the data at once so if I
have a million examples I go through all
the million examples once
in in certain like Foundation models you
may only ever do like two epochs and
those epochs may take many many months
to the point where people don't even
call the meatbox now they just call them
steps like I'm just going to train for a
million steps how do you know that
things are working along that that route
so maybe at step 1000 you want to
validate right or maybe a step 2000 you
validate so that frequency is really up
to your research requirements and that's
what validation step is right it's
calling the validation and the
validation split of the data at a known
interval that the training process is
set up for you and and you've configured
that based on your needs so you could
either train all at once and invalid it
at the end or periodically validate as
your training can you clarify a little
bit on validate versus test is validate
running inferencing and seeing how
accurate is or what does validate mean
yeah so if you have a data set you
basically want to do if you're like in
Academia you want to do three things you
want to take the test so you have a data
set let's say that you have I don't know
60 data points right so you want to take
20 of those data points and put them
aside and never look at them that's
called test set that's like the very
last thing you ever do so the test set
is just like right before you publish
that paper you run that once and that's
the thing you actually report in
Industry we tend not to do that right
tested is kind of like the production
system it's like that's what's happening
in real time so then you have the other
40 data points now that 40 you need to
break up into two sets one for training
and one for validating so just depends
on how much data you have and so on the
rule of thumb is something like 80 20
basically 80 training 20 validation and
then throughout the training process you
can use that validation pretty
frequently to see how you're doing if
your note statistics is like out of
sample testing is what you're doing
right you're just saying hey on this
unseen quantity of data how does my
model perform you need to do that
because if you don't do that you're
going to overfit right and overfitting
means that your model is going to like
memorize the data and not going to be
able to generalize so the validation's
testing how well a model can generalize
yeah generalization that seems like
super important so yeah in in these
different cases you're trying to improve
your performance on data that you didn't
train on so you mentioned some
Integrations we have a previous episode
on feature stores can you explain what
feature stores are just briefly and then
kind of what how lightning works with
them or or interacts with them
yeah so let's say you build a lightning
workflow now that maybe trains a model
and then deploys a model right so you
use the lighting flow to do that and the
lighting Works you'd have one lightning
work for the train one lightning work
for the deploy and then the lighting
flow is the orchestrator that
coordinates both right so the feature
store would basically be something that
you plug into the training work where
what you do is you process the data sets
ahead of time and then let's say it's
like images maybe tabular data is better
you process a data set ahead of times
and you do transforms like you normalize
time so that it's like on a clock or
whatever people are doing nowadays maybe
you normalize by age whatever the
categorical values are and that process
can be pretty expensive so people do it
ahead of time so it's kind of like
caching the features ahead of time right
so you do that and then you know it
really depends on the feature so you use
I'm sure some of them store them in
memory some of them store them on the
disk itself so those optimizations will
happen but what it'll actually do is it
helps you basically remove all that
pre-processing from your data so it can
actually dramatically speed up train
which is really cool so I recommend it
if you can do it do it for images it's a
little hard to do I think because you
usually want random transforms but maybe
there's like a way that people are doing
it nowadays
so in that sense you might be
calculating these features once but then
it experimentally doing different
training but you don't want to
necessarily redo the features because
that you just trust that that was done
adequately exactly so like certain
features are deterministic like if I
normalize everything by n because n is
the average h on a data set and the data
set's not really changing I'd have to
calculate that over and over again so I
should just cache that and be done with
it and then I can iterate on that for
the next few months in certain use cases
though like computer vision the
pre-processing steps are to randomize
the image and you can basically cache
that but some people use this a way to
augment a data set so if I have 10
images for example and I apply 10 random
augments to each image suddenly have a
data set of 100 images which is cool
right so in that case you could keep
generating infinite versions of those
images in which case you may not be able
to Cache them right
okay and how about data versioning what
are the challenges operational or
otherwise related to data versioning and
again does lightning have any impact on
that or connection to that yeah so again
enlightening what we solve is a
connection problem right so you can
actually plug in other tools that solve
this so we don't have like a data store
we don't have like a data versioning
none of that we but we allow you to plug
in with the other third-party tools that
do that really well right so for data
versioning I think people use like DVC
or something to do this nowadays and
tools like that
it's really hard and it just really
depends on the industry that you want to
do the way that this works with
lightning is at the end of the day all
we care about is where's the data
setting and then what model do you want
to train that data with right how do you
get there and what data version and all
of that is like up to you and the other
tools right so in the data version you
will just have different S3 buckets you
would have different indices on the same
S3 bucket so it just depends on how the
on how that third-party tool operates
right from the lightning perspective
you're just kind of giving it the end
result where you're saying hey use this
version of the data and then off you go
and do your thing okay and we talked a
little bit about tensor board which
maybe is an observability feature how
about logging or monitoring or debugging
are any of those whether it's related to
lightning or not or or can you sort of
explain any machine learning deep
learning specific attributes of those or
is it just similar to any piece of
software no so actually debugging is
something that we spend a lot of time on
and logging so tracking everything that
you're doing and these are all implicit
things on the platform these are on
Facebook features on the platform so if
you go to lighting.ai and you go train a
model there what it'll do is it'll
actually track the logs for you like the
out logs from the machines you also have
an interactive coding environment with
the machines that you're actually
training so you can actually train and
debug in real time so you can like pass
a GPU and see what's happening in that
process and understand I think debug is
probably one of the hardest things to do
in deep learning especially when you're
doing distributed training or
distributed inference so we've done a
ton of work to make sure that like the
same environment that you build your
code it's the same that you goes into
production so you can take you can take
the stuff that you built in kind of like
your your workspace where you're
developing on the cloud and then ship
that as your production environments out
of the box right so that you know
there's no real gap between how you
developed and how you actually ship
things this is really important because
you know we've done this in the past as
well we can simulate stuff on your
laptop all day long but we I can't
simulate 70 terabytes of that on your
laptop right so it's just really hard to
actually like you know I like to the
phrase was like train how you fight
right so it's like you have to really
really be in that same environment so
that's a lot of what we try to do on the
cloud and I would say it's probably one
of the big benefits of um the platform
can you mention a specific bug when you
were sort of confounded or confused and
then were able to figure it out you or
or your users
yeah so I mean luckily uh you know the
tools are pretty robust nowadays so most
of the bugs that we're debugging are
like distributed training bugs there was
definitely a period where like oh man is
this what's going on here that we save
the right checkpoint like did the right
metrics go in there I think the most
subtle things to debug are like I
personally I hate these kind of bugs but
when you're doing distributed training
and you're calculating something on two
separate processes on two different gpus
and then you average them or something
and then you're like gradients go to
zero and you're like ah what happened
right so when the gradients go to zero
you're done like the or sorry not zero
they go to Nan so basically like the
models just can't learn anymore that's
the word so debugging nands and usually
that process means you have to like
pause the machines while they're doing
the distributed training together and
then go inspect each GPU independently
at the same time see what the values are
in that process see like what is X right
there printed out and then do the
competition by hand so you do like the
all reduce or the average yourself and
then probably what you realize is that
your position is wrong right maybe your
position was set to 32 bits and then it
turns out that the output of that is
actually 64-bit so it blows up the
Precision so it usually comes down to
some sort of setting like that also I
think if you do kind of bypass that and
you're like okay I solved why that stand
if you calculate a gradient then and
basically your weights are like either
too high or too low and then you
actually apply the update rule to it
when you back prop then you're going to
end up exploding the weights which means
that the network also doesn't learn
anything so hopefully you don't run into
these bugs because if you're using
models already kind of pre-built for you
these things are already solved but I
would say those are the hardest bugs to
debug mostly because of how you have to
actually interact with the machines at
the same time
what does it mean to decouple data from
the model from the hardware I can sort
of imagine the hardware in terms of you
want to be able to train with different
vendors or or different types of
Hardware but how about those three
layers decoupling the data from the
model from the hardware
so remember that most of what we've been
doing not just us but the AI Community
as a whole has been to figure out how do
you structure code for deep learning
like what are the right obstructions
right we didn't know any of this
software engineering's known this for 20
30 40 years at this point in AI we don't
know like should the data be coupled to
the model like there was a point in time
2014 through 2017 18 maybe even 19 where
when you saw code written it was models
that were like specifically written for
a data set right and it was like well
it's not really the right way to go like
should you re should this model really
be written for mnist and then you go try
a different data set and I have to
rewrite the model for imagenet or
whatever it is so we've learned as a
society now that we need to decouple
these things because it means I can take
a model and then swap the data sets to
it so that I can iterate quickly I can
try things locally and then on the cloud
right so I think it's a necessary evil
it also makes model more agnostic as
models have evolved into like llms and
Foundation models turns out that you can
use the same architecture for different
data sets right which is really cool so
you no longer have to write like a
specialized model for a specialized data
set so all in all I think a net a net
positive what's happened there the data
separation side something I saw recently
was they were able to use I think it was
stable diffusion which is normally about
generating images to generate
spectrograms which could be turned into
audio files I don't know if you saw yeah
that sounds pretty generalized yeah
exactly it's interesting I mean like you
know I saw it a few days ago and I I'm
not actually I haven't looked into it
but like I'm not actually sure of the
viability of that like so we did a lot
of work on text to speech right and a
lot of how you do that work is you have
to generate spectrograms and then you
use a CNN convolutional Network to
actually output stuff so spectrograms or
images at the end of the day they can be
viewed as images which is why this kind
of works that my question is like will
it actually encode the correct waveform
terms in the way that they're supposed
to like maybe it'll output a spectrogram
that like yes if you play it it will
sound like music but like is it actually
cohesively put together is there
actually thought behind it I'm not sure
but I think it's like a really
interesting Avenue and I think it opens
the door to get there I think to get
that to work you probably have to take
that diffusion model and probably cop
like attach it to another model that can
actually more like guide how the
decoding is happening under the hood so
that it's not just kind of randomly put
into the spectrogram lightning is built
on pie torch and we've been focusing on
Pi torch but you did mention that you
can train tensorflow models with
lightning are there any projects or
types of projects where you think
tensorflow is in fact the right approach
these days or how would you guide
someone towards Pi torture
yeah I mean we're fully a pie to our
shop in general right so I don't
personally use tensorflow I haven't in a
long time we mostly enable this because
we have clients who have Legacy code who
do it like I think Frameworks that
converge largely at this point so Pi
Torch versus tensorflow I think that's
like a 20 2019 20 debate today I don't
think it's really a debate it's more
like I don't know do you like red cars
or blue cars like it's kind of
preference at this point and I think
both have a lot of similar features
nowadays both have a lot of the same
kind of design mechanisms under the hood
so it just comes to the experience and
like what feels better to you right to
me pytorch feels better but that's
personal preference so I don't know I
can't say because I'm not an expert at
tensorflow user but we see our clients
using it still and I don't know the use
cases I think you could probably do the
same use cases with both Frameworks
right I'm not sure yeah I've definitely
seen that with other open source
projects where they have quote unquote
competitors but they end up being both
so feature folded they can clearly both
do the job and it does come down down to
maybe either preference or just other
constraints you have or Staffing who
knows who knows how to use it yeah I
mean I tend to look at things beyond
that like I tend to look at
how open source is it and what are the
motivations of the people behind it
right so one thing that I've noticed is
that a lot of these open source
libraries are built by big tech
companies where today their incentives
are aligned with open source largely but
that might change when a recession comes
so what happens to those projects right
I'm not talking about Pi torture
tensorflow specifically I'm saying there
have been times where like projects come
off from companies big tech companies
that are open source and then those
people get promoted and then they leave
and then they kind of leave you hanging
with the project and you're like well is
anyone maintaining this anymore and
that's just kind of how it works at
Facebook like you're motivated
internally to build things ship them and
then but you're not like incentivized to
maintain them right so that that's kind
of my main concern generally is if
you're going to use open source like are
the companies behind them open source
themselves like lightning is fully open
source like our job is to provide open
source software right it's not like we
have a different agenda so those are
kind of considerations that I would look
into as well when using any any open
source code
you touched on this but can you contrast
the needs of academic researchers
compared to commercial users like I said
I think you kind of alluded to some of
these differences but just to be clear
what differences have you seen I think
academics are more I would say they
overlap a lot more than more than people
think but academics are more interested
in the understanding and experimentation
face of things industry is more
interested in like kind of running
things once or twice maybe and then
doing something with the output of that
they care less about what happens under
the hood and they care more about the
outputs whereas in Academia they really
care about like every part of that and
they want to understand every single
detail as they should because that's
what their phds are usually about
and sometimes they'll create novel ways
of doing it right so maybe
I don't know I guess it's really more
expected that the researchers will be
caring more about trying to push
something novel at this point but
there's not really a lot of Novel things
that you can push in the tooling side
anymore it's really on the algorithm and
the data side right okay we're going to
start wrapping up are there any
resources or documentation that you
would like to recommend for someone to
get started with pytorch and lightning
yeah so we actually just launched a
class deep learning fundamentals and
this takes people from completely
knowing nothing about deep learning to
learning about it fully so it's
Lightning's class for teaching you about
deep learning right so that's on our
website it's sliding.ai and then search
for deep learning fundamentals there and
that's taught by uh our lead educator
Sebastian rashka so he's a associate
professor at University of
Wisconsin-Madison as well and he I think
is one of the best Educators in the
world so we partner together to
basically bring Master Class level to
this and we envisioned lightning as
being a platform where you'll be able to
learn about any machine learning Topic
in like a very beautiful and intuitive
way as well
how about the user Community a thriving
user Community is an important feature
in a platform these days aside from this
course you just mentioned how are you
nurturing a healthy user community and
kind of what type of community do you
feel you have around lightning
lighting is all about Community that's
kind of bread and butter and it's
everything that we've built and done
everything that we do is for the
community I mean every decision that we
make on the tools every decision that we
we take with classes it's all how do we
empower the community more our community
lives a lot in slack and we have forums
as well on the website so definitely if
you're not on the slack join it but the
way I think about it is you know
sometimes it can be lonely in machine
learning and we want people to work
together and just like make friends and
like have you know same interests work
on really cool things everyone in the
lion Community is like an expert at this
stuff and even newer people who are
coming in and learning about this so I
would say like if you're kind of
starting out in deep learning and you're
just kind of getting into it I would
join the community there's like a lot of
stuff that people will help you they'll
teach you things and also if you've
never contributed to open source like
it's a really cool way to do it
contribute to any repo we specifically
have like issues that are tagged for you
to learn but what's cool is I will help
you land those pull requests and we'll
teach you software engineering on the
process so don't be shy I mean my first
pull request ever was like documentation
like that was amazing so go for it yeah
that's an interesting point that you
could have people who are really
interested in deep learning and AI but
they don't necessarily have software
engineering skills to start and it sort
of becomes a something they can do to
extend their reach or or to give them
more ability to impact on these projects
is by learning essentially to program
exactly and we even have a class for
that also it's called software
engineering for researchers so we teach
you all those like how to use git and
what are notebooks and how to think
about scripts and you know it's like
when you show up to a PhD and you're
like never really done software
engineering there's like a whole year
where you're like how did you guys learn
all these things that's the stuff we
teach in that class what upcoming
lightning features or releases are you
most looking forward to I guess this is
in any time in 2023 at this point yeah
so the main thing that we released now
is fabric right so fabric allows you to
build your own training Loops allows you
to build your own trainer gives you full
control when you want it and when you
don't wanna you can use a trainer as
well so that's really cool that I think
my opinion this is like the last deep
learning framework you'll ever need
because I'm not sure how much more
flexibility we could give you at this
point so that's really cool and then the
other main theme for us is we are
empowering people to build their kind of
like ml startups and AI products with
lightning now right so if you want to
launch the next stable diffusion company
or the next open AI like we have a
platform for you to do that now very
very easily you you no longer have to
raise 10 million dollars and hire 50
people it's one person can do it in a
few weeks which is really cool
you've talked about creating an
operating system for artificial
intelligence I think this is going to be
the last question where do you think
lighting is today relative to being an
operating system and what additional
features do you think are necessary to
realize that vision
so an operating system has a few parts
to it right it has a scheduler it has
like memory it has the execution of
programs it has the hardware that it's
running on the machine and so on I'm not
an OS expert but I think there's like
one or two missing in there I think we
have a lot of pieces today there's you
know we're still thinking about like
what is the equivalent of memory for our
platform so the hardware the laptop is
the cloud right so that's what we have
today lightning AI so you can kind of
sign up and and create your own clusters
and all of that so you have the hardware
there you have the orchestration
mechanism like the what runs apps how
they do it and so on so that's the
lightning framework so what used to be
called pytosh lightning that's there
under the hood already
and then the ability to connect data
then you have the ability for memory as
well so the ability to share between
apps and I guess what's interesting to
me is that like it's an operating system
for AI really going to be the same as an
operating system for a laptop it may not
be because an operating system for AI
may have to account for the fact that
you have multiple machines huge data
sets these are things that you didn't
have to account for in a laptop for
example so what are other considerations
that are going to happen I don't know
and that's really exciting to me because
it means that as the world evolves and
we learn what we actually need to do
deep learning I will be able to bake
that in
you mentioned the lightning.ai website
and there was a course there I think
maybe two courses you mentioned where
else would you like to point people to
to find out more about lightning or
yourself yeah I saw it on their website
right so if you go to lighting.ai there
are examples there that you can play
with there's a ton of documentation
create an account you're going to get
free credits every month so you can run
you can code in the cloud you can do
your research there you can train on
gpus you can deploy things and all of it
is centralized so we have the forums we
have the community there if you have any
questions please please ask don't be shy
we're super excited to help we're super
excited to teach you how to code and
we're super excited to teach how to do
open source do deep learning data
science all of that and I think you're
stepping in at the right time because I
think this is the next big thing like in
general I think the first was web second
was mobile third is AI right so the next
billion dollar companies are going to be
AI companies and I hope that all of you
guys will build them how about social
media is there a place people can follow
you yeah so we have a Twitter accounts
you can look it up it's lightning Ai and
then we also have LinkedIn accounts
there as well we do have a newsletter so
if you want to keep up to date with
what's happening in ai go to LinkedIn
and sign up for a newsletter there we
will let you know what are the latest
interesting things in research what are
the latest things in engineering for
deep learning data science what are
startups working on so keep up also in
the community that way okay I'll put
links to those into the four episodes I
mentioned in the show notes I really
enjoyed talking with you today William
yeah thank you Philip this is really fun
I hope everyone gets a lot of value out
of this great this is Philip Winston for
software engineering radio thanks for
listening
thanks for listening to SC radio an
educational program brought to you by
Tripoli software magazine for more about
the podcast including other episodes
visit our website at se.radio.net
[Music]
feedback you can comment on each episode
on the website or reach us on LinkedIn
Facebook Twitter or through our slack
Channel at SC radio dot slack.com you
can also email us at team sc-radio.net
this and all other episodes of SC radio
is licensed under created Commons
license 2.5 thanks for listening
[Music]